ILGWU Memorabilia 5780 MB
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Certificate from State of Arkansas, 1957; Memorabilia (Box 26, Folder 7)
  To All who shall see these presents, greeting: Know ye, that the Governor of the State of Arkansas.S.C. Chaikin, Arkansas Traveler, who is hereby authorized and commissioned to serve as an Ambassador of Good Will.
- Program and souvenir pens from ILGWU, Local 178 Golden Anniversary. Dinner, 1984; Memorabilia (Box 26, Folder 8)
  Program for ILGWU, Local 178, Fall River, Mass., Golden Anniversary Dinner. And two ball point pens
- Certificate from Fashion Institute of Technology, 1990; Memorabilia (Box 26, Folder 9)
  Certification of the appointment of Sol C. Chaikin, as Trustee of the College by New York City Board of Education for a term to expire June 30, 1990
- Certificate - Mr. and Mrs. David Dubinsky, Memorabilia (Box 26, Folder 10)
  Certificate - Mr. and Mrs. David Dubinsky are Founders of the American Symphony Orchestra
- ILGWU - pins, medals, 1937-1986; Memorabilia (Box 26, Folder 11)
  Medal - Exec Vice Pres. - ILGWU Thirty-Ninth Convention, Hollywood, Florida; pins - ILGWU, AF of L, GEB Bienvenu a Montreal Welcome; ILGWU, Organized 1900; Tippecanoe and Tyler too
- ILGWU "Fight Nazism and Fascism" poster (Mitchell Loeb, 1934), and misc. ILGWU posters (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Justice Menu; Proclamation from the Office of the Mayor, City of New York (declaring) March 21st to 29th, 1961 as New York's Spring Festival of Fashion Week (Box 28, Folder 1)
- ILGWU clothing, Memorabilia (Box 29, Folder 1)
  Dress - blue/green dress with pleated skirt, union label material; Skirt - multi-color union label material, pleated; One piece uniform - denim union label material - zip up front
- ILGWU clothing, Memorabilia (Box 30, Folder 1)
  Small aprons - multi-color union label material; Dress - denim union label material; Dress - blue bodice with multi-color union label sleeves and pleated skirt; Skirt - red and white striped
- ILGWU cloth bags, Memorabilia (Box 31, Folder 1)
  Cloth, canvas bags in various sizes unions on the labels are as follows -- UNITE!; NTC, UAW- Daimler Chrysler National Training Center; UAW-GM Center for Human Resources our people make the difference; Coalition of Labor Union Women; International Labor Communications Association, AFL-CIO/CLC; 7 bags that say Save the Garment Com
- Sewing kit -- "Look for this Union Label" (Box 32, Folder 2)
- ILGWU stamps (raised seal presses), Memorabilia (Box 32, Folder 1)
  raised seal imprints - 1- Knitted Garment Workers Union, Local 155; Textile Trimming Workers Union T.T.W.U., wooden stamp - is the ILGWU union label stamp, one other hand raised stamp, doesn't appear to work, so not sure what the seal says
- The Spirit of '89, 1950; Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 20)
  [metal] - This memento - Presented to our brother and sister delegates and honored guests at the historic ILGWU GOLDEN JUBILEE CONVENTION, Atlantic City - 1950
- Fiftieth Anniversary Coins from the First Union Health Center: 1914-1964, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 21)
  2 bronze coins
- ILGWU badges - orig. owned by Ms. Mary Goff Schuster - transferred from 5780/022 (box 17), 1937-1980; Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 1)
  Delegate and Guest badges from ILGWU conventions
- ILGWU buttons/pins, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 2)
  Buttons - Picture of Uncle Sam laying in a bed with the caption "Health Care for All"
- ILGWU rubber stamp, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 3)
  One with Ronald Alman's signature; one with "I.L.G.W.U. Local 575 (and their address); one with "Northeast, Western PA & Ohio Dept. (and their address); last one says "This Applicant Exempted From Initiation Fee"
- ILGWU rubber stamp, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 4)
  One says "Reagan "Maybe" Hazardous to Your Health"; other one says "Central Pennsylvania District Council, I.L.G.W.U."
- Award, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 5)
  "State of New York Executive Dept. W. Averell Harriman, Governor -- To Whom these Presents shall come, Greeting: Pauline Newmanthis twenty-second day of august in the year of our Lord, One Thousand Nine Hundred Fifty-Five"
- Plaque, 1975; Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 6)
  Wooden plaque with picture of Sol Chaikin - "The Martin Luther King, Jr. Democrats Salute Sol "Chick" Chaikin an outstanding New Yorker, who stands tall in the field of organized labor16th day of August, 1975"
- Notepad, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 7)
  Memo (pad) with a ILGWU union label on the heading
- ILGWU Wage Record Book; ILGWU Union Label (flyer), Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 8)
  Empty "Wage Record Book"; Flyer listing Promotional items
- ILGWU Award, 1981; Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 9)
  "International Labor Press Association AFL-CIO/CLC, Film and Broadcast Competition 1981 Award of Honor presented to Northeast ILGWU Departmentthe 13th day of November in the year nineteen-hundred and eighty-one"
- ILGWU - flyer, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 10)
  See America in style: A travel and fashion guide
- ILGWU pens and nail file, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 11)
  2 pens with the ILGWU union label on them, and an emory board (nail file) also with the ILGWU union label
- ILGWU - jar opener, sponge, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 12)
  Round rubber jar opener with a picture of the ILGWU union label; sponge - "Before you buy, insist on the ILGWU Label in all women's and children's apparel" with the pic of ILGWU union label
- ILGWU balloons, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 13)
  Green, orange, red, yellow balloons with the ILGWU union label on them
- ILGWU- memo books, rulers, tape measure, rain hat, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 14)
  All items have the ILGWU union label on them
- ILGWU- sewing kit, scissors, folder, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 15)
  Foler is labelled "Local 10, ILGWU"; scissors are made of cardboard and used for advertising ILGWU; small sewing kit, for advertising ILGWU
- ILGWU - Rainbows - ILGWU Worker-Family Education Program, Local 23-25-Chinatown Site, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 16)
  A copy of the Student Magazine "Rainbows"
- ILGWU - pins, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 17)
  Union label pin; 1994 ILGWU pin
- ILGWU coasters, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 18)
  Knitgoods Workers Union, ILGWU, AFL-CIO, Local 155, 50th Anniversary
- ILGWU seal press, Memorabilia (Box 33, Folder 19)
  ILGWU seal
- ILGWU calendars, 1971-1972; Memorabilia (Box 34, Folder 1)
  ILGWU calendars for the years 1971 and 1972 (in mapcase)
- Plastic bag with union slogans printed on it, Memorabilia (Box 35, Folder 1)
  Plastic bag, (red, white, blue) with union slogans printed on it
- Emergency sleeve for car antenna (ILGWU), Memorabilia (Box 35, Folder 2)
  HELP sign to be placed on a car antenna in case of emergency - with the ILGWU union label pinned on it
- Plaque - Coalition of Labor Union Women, 1981; Memorabilia (Box 35, Folder 3)
  Coalition of Labor Union Women, New York State Award Sol C. Chaikin, October 17, 1981.
- Award, 1955; Memorabilia (Box 35, Folder 4)
  The Histadrut Hao??dim presents this Scroll of Honor to David Gingold.Medical Center at Kiriat Shmone, Israel.October 25, 1955
- Award, 1978; Memorabilia (Box 35, Folder 5)
  Sol C. Chaikin '38 is awarded the Townsend Harris Medal by the Alumni Association of the City College of New York
- Advertisement, 1938; Memorabilia (Box 35, Folder 6)
  Learn and play in your union Union Member go to school, Fall 1938 Catalog, Local 22 Union School.
- Sign, Memorabilia (Box 35, Folder 7)
  White plastic sign with lettering -- Immigration Project (and an ILGWU union label)
- Award, 1943; Memorabilia (Box 35, Folder 8)
  We express our profound pride in David Gingold Son of Waterproof Garment Workers Union, Local 20-ILGWU
- Small flags, Memorabilia (Box 36, Folder 1)
  Triangle shaped flags -- yellow nylon material, very wrinkled, with CLUW decal in the center, lettering - "ILGWU Chinese Committee", "CLUW" -- they also have Chinese characters on them
- Banner/flag, Memorabilia (Box 36, Folder 2)
  Red cotton cloth - With a white decal in the center - "Liberty & Union ILGWU" with a picture of the face of the Statue of Liberty
- Banner/flag, Memorabilia (Box 36, Folder 3)
  Hand painted flag/banner -- yellow cotton material, ILGWU union label, Chinese characters, "23-25 Chinese Retirees Club", "Local 23-25 ILGWU"
- Banner/flag, Memorabilia (Box 36, Folder 4)
  White nylon material with scalloped bottom -- "Swinging 10", "Local 10 I.L.G.W.U.", Musical notes and conductor w/scissors pictured
- Lions Club award, 1994; Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 1)
  New York City Hall Lions Club presents to Mr. Edgar Romney, Manager-Secretary, Local 23-25 ILGWU, for his generous and continued support to Lionism, Yvonne Louie, President - 11/11/1994
- Award for Edgar Romney, 1989; Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 2)
  Congratulations Edgar Romney on your election to Executive Vice-President of the ILGWU, June 9, 1989, Hilario Chajet, Frank Altruda, Geoffrey Bauman, Isabel Casilla, Gladys Castilla, Jose Del Rosario, Jose Garcia, Doris Rhiman, Margarita Rios, Rose Ton
- Award from American ORT Federation, 1985; Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 3)
  For the children of ORT this Multiple Scholarship Award is presented to Edgar Romney in appreciation of your dedication to the principles of ORT and your generosity which will make the dreams of today the realities of tomorrow for children at ORT schools, American ORT Federation
- Award from American ORT Federation, 1990; Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 4)
  Presented to Edgar Romney in deep appreciation for serving as Chairman American Labor ORT Chapter, tribute to Jay Mazur American ORT Federation, June 13, 1990
- Award from the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1995; Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 5)
  The New York Branch National Association for the Advancement of Colored People presents its 84th Anniversary Exemplar Award to May Ying Chen for continued outstanding courage in the struggle for civil rights for all, June 2, 1995, Annie B. Martin President
- ILGWU hats, place card, Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 6)
  ILGWU cotton hats (2), ILGWU, Local 10 place card
- ILGWU - bumper sticker, letter openers, ruler, Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 7)
  Live better, work union, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union AFL-CIO (bumper sticker); Int. Ladies Garment Workers Union, Union Made ILGWU (letter openers); 6" plastic ruler
- Banner/flag, Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 8)
  Cristoforo Colombo, Labor Omnia Vincit, Italian Dressmakers Union - Local 89 - I.L.G.W.U.
- ILGWU key chains; ILGWU pin, 1983; Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 9)
  Gold colored - 60th Anniversary Knitgoods Workers Union, Service Standards Strength, 1983; Pin has fake diamond like stones that make the letters of ILGWU
- ILGWU paper eight, 1983; Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 10)
  Knitgoods Workers Union, I.L.G.W.U. AFL-CIO, Local 155, 50th Anniversary, 1983
- Certificate of Recognition; ILGWU Award; George Meany Award; ILGWU Award, 1987-1994; Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 11)
  Certificate of Recognition presented to Edgar Romney, In recognition of your outstanding participation and contribution to your community.presented this date of Saturday, May 30, 1987; Award presented to ILGWU, Local 23-25 in recognition of your contribution as a program partner to the National Workplace Literacy Program. With much gratitude, Chinatown manpower Project, Inc., May 20, 1994; The George Meany Award for Outstanding Service to Youth is presented to: Edgar Romney6-26-89; The International Ladies Garment Workers Union, Presented to The Student Council, in recognition o four outstanding and dedicated work on this 5th day of June 1992
- CBTU paper weight, 2002; Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 12)
  CBTU, Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, Cleveland Robinson Award, Presented to Edgar Romney, In recognition and grateful appreciation of your advocacy and steadfast commitment to achieving workers rights and global fairness, 31st International Convention, Las Vegas, Nevada, May 26, 2002
- ILGWU pin cushion, Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 13)
  Hat shaped pin cushion, made out of ILGWU material (multi-colored)
- ILGWU 'house', Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 14)
  Cloth house made out of ILGWU material (multi-colored)
- Assorted badges - moved from 5780/087, 1965-1980; Memorabilia (Box 37, Folder 15)
  ILGWU Guest badge; ILGWU, 36th Convention Press badge (1977); ILGWU, 37th Convention Press badge (1980); AFL-CIO Press badge, 6th Biennial Convention (1965); ILGWU, 38th Convention Press badge (1983); AFL-CIO Press badge, 9th Biennial Convention (1971); ILGWU, 34th Convention Press badge (1971)
- Proclamation, 2001; Memorabilia (Box 38, Folder 1)
  For giving the most in the name of those who have the least; For welcoming those who had little welcome; and for building the strength that builds opportunity Edgar Romney. The Working Families Party is proud to honor you as a fighter for working families. Friday, November 30th, 2001
- ILGWU broadside, Memorabilia (Box 38, Folder 2)
  Picture of a little black boy with the quote "I have a dream that my four little children will one day live in a nation where they will not be judged by the color of their skin but by the content of their character"
- ILGWU sign, Memorabilia (Box 38, Folder 3)
  Workers of are on strike, Knitgoods Worker's Union, Local 155, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, AFL-CIO
- watercolor picture, 1989; Memorabilia (Box 38, Folder 4)
  Congratulations to May Ying Chen on her service to the Dinkins Transition Committee diligent and caring kind and respected wholehearted service a pride to the Chinese Community.
- Charter, United Hebrew Trades, 1945; Memorabilia (Box 38, Folder 5)
  Charter, United Hebre Trades of the State of New York, Hereby grant this charter to Sam Sinensky, Louis Nelso, Paul Tauber, Louis Levinson, William Schaffer, Isidore Berezin, Al Epstein.25th day of April 1945
- Charter, ILGWU, 1956; Memorabilia (Box 38, Folder 6)
  International Ladies Garment Workers' Union doth grant this Charter to Julia Gaud, .this twentieth day of January One thousand nine hundred and fifty-six
- Award - Educational and Cultural Fund of the Electrical Industry, Memorabilia (Box 38, Folder 7)
  The Trustees Educational and Cultural Fund of the Electrical Industry are privileged to honor Blouse, Skirts and Sportswear Workers Union, Local 23-25 I.L.G.W.U.
- 48 star American flag, Memorabilia (Box 39, Folder 1)
  American Flag - 48 star
- ILGWU banner, Memorabilia (Box 40, Folder 1)
  Red felt banner with yellow lettering, scalloped bottom with yellow tassels -- "Dress Waist Pressers Union, Local 60, I.L.G.W.U. New York City" (ILGWU emblem in center of banner)
- Banner: ILGWU SLAUTES AMERICA, Banners (Box 41, Folder 1)
  White vinyl banner, with blue around the edge, blue lettering ILGWU, and red lettering SALUTES AMERICA -- dirty, needs cleaning, and fading -- 12' x 5' -- letters appear to have been painted on banner
- Funeral procession for victims of the Triangle Fire - [enlarged photograph on a frame: 3'x3'11"], Black and white photograph (Box 42, Folder 1)
- Photo of women walking down the driveway at Unity House (?) - side by side with their arms around each other and smiling. [photo with a metal backing: 2'8" x 3'6"], Black and white photograph (Box 42, Folder 2)
- Images digitized from the collection., Black and white photograph (Box 44)
  - Plastic ILGWU apron (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Sewing kits (2); ILGWU address books; Local 11 cloth money bag (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Plastic bag - red/white/blue - lettered with ILGWU and Union labels (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Cotton Jacket - White with blue lettering [back] Phila-South Jersey District Council; [front left lapel] Union label (Box 46, Folder 1)
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 45)
- Paper shopping bag from the ILGWU - 'Judy Bond Inc. On Strike Don't Buy Judy Bond Blouses [red, white, and blue] (Box 46, Folder 5)
- flyer - "Retailers! See How Others Participate and Profit! "Hallmark of Fashion" Promotion" (Box 47, Folder 3)
  brittle, torn
- Paper shopping bag w/handle - "Look for this LABELin ladies' and children's wear" (Box 47, Folder 2)
- Letter openers (2); raincoats in pockets (3); key chains (2); comb in pocket (1); heart shaped mini pillows (2); ruler (Box 47, Folder 1)
  Key chains - "Canada Etiquette Syndicale Union Label"; rain coats - "Demandez Cette Etiquiette et Votre Elegance est Assuree", "Fashion A Start is Born to guide your wardrobe buying"; letter openers - "Union internationale des ouvriers du vetement pour dames"; heart shaped mini pillows - "Look For This Union Label When You Shop", "Hallmark of Fashion"; comb - "Hallmark of Fashion Cachet de L'Elegance"; ruler - "International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union"